PHD STUDENT IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

Tehran, Iran

"Be the change that you want to see in the world."

Summary

My name is Farhad Hamidi, currently a PhD student in mechanical engineering at Amirkabir University of Technology in Tehran. I earned my master's degree in mechanical engineering with a focus on applied design from Shahid Beheshti University and I graduated as the 2nd-ranked among M.Sc. students.

I began my professional experience in the field of rotating equipment at the consulting engineering company "Tadbir and Fan Asia." I am familiar with standards such as API-610, API-620, API-674, API-650, and ASME BPVC. Additionally, I have work experience at the Abadan Oil Refinery, where I dealt with various process equipment such as pumps, valves, heat exchangers, and more. I am proficient in reading process flow diagrams (P&ID) and piping and instrumentation diagrams (P&ID).

I am well-versed in various mechanical software and technical documents, including specifications, datasheets, material requisitions (MR), and technical bid evaluations (TBE). Some of my ethical qualities include a strong work ethic, adaptability to the environment, responsibility, an interest in teamwork, collaboration beyond job duties, and a high learning ability.

Education

Amirkabir University of Technology

Tehran, Iran

PHD STUDENT IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

Sep. 2023 - present

- Field of study: Dynamics, vibrations and control
- Selected as the Exceptionally Talented Student in the PhD program (Admitted without exam)

Shahid Beheshti University

Tehran, Iran

M.Sc. in Mechanical Engineering

Oct. 2021 - Sep. 2023

- **GPA**: 17.64/20
- Field of study: Dynamics, vibrations and control
- Ranked **2nd** among 17 M.Sc. students of Mechanical engineering(Applied Design)
- Thesis: Autonomous Navigation in Unknown Environment for Differential Drive Robot Using Reinforcement Learning

Petroleum University of Technology

Abadan, Khuzestan, Iran

Sep. 2017 - Aug. 2021

B.Sc. IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

- **GPA**: 16.82/20
- Ranked 2nd among 23 B.Sc. students of Mechanical engineering
- Thesis: Ultrasonic Nondestructive Evaluation Using Artificial Intelligence (19.75/20)

Work Experience_

Mehanical Engineer Abadan, Iran

ABADAN OIL REFINERY

Nov. 2022 - Aug. 2023

- Reading and interpreting PFD (Process Flow Diagram) and P&ID (Piping and Instrumentation Diagram) drawings.
- · Familiarity with pumps and valves
- · Knowledge of other process equipment such as heat exchangers, compressors, distillation columns, etc.
- Collaborating with other engineering disciplines to ensure the integration of mechanical systems within the refinery.
- Providing technical support to operations personnel during plant shutdowns or emergencies.

Rotating equipment engineer

Tehran, Iran

Jun. 2022 – Oct. 2022

TADBIR VA FAN-E ASIA CONSULTING ENGINEERS

- Meets with clients' technical staff to discuss technical information and features.
- Prepares sketches and performs calculations for a detailed segment of a project.
- Prepares equipment specifications, inquiry and purchase requisitions for approval.
- Evaluates vendors' bids and drawings to assure compliance with specifications.
- Participates in the preparation of equipment Specification, Datasheet,...

Computer & Programming Skills

Enineering softwares ROS, Gazebo, Solidworks, Simatic Manager, FLuidSIM, Catia, Abaqus

Programming languages Python, MATLAB

> Python libraries NumPy, Matplotlib, Pandas, Tensorflow

Other Softwares Microsoft Office

Academic Projects

Build Software for FEM Analysis of 2D and 3D Truss

Tehran, Iran

FFM COURSE

· Using App Designer and Matlab Software.

Tehran, Iran

Modeling and Control of 3-DOF Articulated Manipulators (RRR) using MRCs

Feb. 2023 - Jun. 2023

Feb. 2023 - Jun. 2023

Sep. 2022 - Feb. 2023

Feb. 2021 - Jun. 2021

Oct. 2023 - Des. 2023

ADAPTIVE CONTROL course · Using Simulink and Matlab Software.

Bearing Features Extraction Using Python

Tehran, Iran

SIGNAL PROCESSING course

Using Numpy, Pandas and Matplotlib.

See project in Github

Design Controller Using PID and Pole Placement Methods

Tehran, Iran

ADVANCED CONTROL course

• Design Controller for Balance Rotary Inverted Pendulum.

Abadan, Iran

Abadan, Iran

Image-based surface defect detection using convolutional neural network

FRACTURE MECHANICS course

· Using QT Quick and Python programming language, I build a composite question calculator software.

Create artificial neural network model for predict crack depth and length

BACHELOR PROJECT

BACHELOR PROJECT

Nov. 2020 - Jun. 2021

• Using Python programming language and Deep Learning libraries

Abadan, Iran

Feature extraction from ultrasonic signals and create dataset

Nov. 2020 - Jun. 2021

• Using Python programming language and Feature extraction libraries

Build composite Calculator software using Python and Qt Creator

Abadan, Iran

Feb. 2021 - Jun. 2021

• Using QT Quick and Python programming language, I build a composite question calculator software.

· See project in YouTube

COMPOSITE COURSE PROJECT

Do a project using MSP software for a project control management course PROJECT CONTROL MANAGEMENT COURSE

Abadan, Iran Sep. 2020 - Jan. 2021

• Extracted WBS using MindView software and calculate project progress,... using MSP software.

Simulation the bottoming steam Rankine cycle (SRC) and organic Rankine cycle (ORC) systems for a triple combined system using gas turbine (GT) as topping cycle

Abadan, Iran

ADVANCED ENERGY SYSTEMS COURSE Sep. 2020 - Jan. 2021

• In this project, using Ebsilon Software and python(CoolProp Library), I simulate a triple combined system(SRC-ORC-GT).

Static analysis and calculation of stress concentration factor in four geometries

Abadan, Iran

FINITE ELEMENT METHOD COURSE Sep. 2020 - Jan. 2021

• In this project, with using Ansys Apol software and finite element method (FEM), I calculate stress concentration factor and maximum stress in four geometries.

Honors & Awards

Ranked 2nd, among 17 M.Sc. students of Mechanical Engineering(Applied Design), Shahid Beheshti 2021-2023 university

Top 3%, Iran M.Sc. entrance exam(konkour) in Mechanical Engineering 2021

2017-2021 Ranked 2nd, among 23 B.Sc. students of Mechanical Engineering, Petroleum university of technology

Top 5%, Iran B.Sc. entrance exam(konkour) among 3rd exam region applicants 2017



Advanced structural mechanics journal

Shahrekord, Iran

A NOVEL METHOD FOR DETECTING THE TYPE OF SURFACE DEFECTS OF HOT ROLLED STEEL STRIP USING THE CONVOLUTIONAL

NEURAL NETWORK

May. 2023

Seyed Mohammad Hossein Sharifi, **Farhad Hamidi**, Sajjad Chabokru

Certificates

Learning SOLIDWORKS: For Students, Engineers, and Designers

Udemy Oct. 2021

SEE CREDENTIAL

Creditional ID:UC-b01bcb60-d5a4-4639-b9c3-6fe22d4cdc3d

Programming for Everybody (Getting Started with Python)

coursera Sep. 2020

Creditional ID:a061ebbfb835b8c8f34940219385da0f

What is Data Science?

coursera Nov. 2020

SEE CREDENTIAL
Creditional ID:64dcf1c84c2cf6dcb3db2bdc6f9bdb98

Refinery processes

Petro Paydar Iranian

SEE CREDENTIAL

SEE CREDENTIAL

Mar. 2020

Creditional ID:PHASE13-308

PFD P&ID

Petro Paydar Iranian

SEE CREDENTIAL

Mar. 2020

Creditional ID:PHASE13-446

Languages.

English

Limited working proficiency

Arabic

Native

Persian

Native